钓鱼和狩猎是雅库蒂亚食物的重要来源
fishing and hunting are important sources of food in yakutia
整个村庄都聚集在一起钓鱼，聚集在一起参加这项巨大
because it's simply impossible to grow fruits and vegetables due to the harsh climate
的钓鱼活动，尤其是彼此帮助和支持，尤其是在食物方面，
in the late autumn before the cold winter comes yogurts are preparing for their annual
他们知道，如果没有彼此的帮助，每年秋天都很难生存，
traditional fishing event known as munkha munkha is a traditional ice fishing using a seine net
这很难生存在曼哈顿，一年一度的冰钓钓鱼者可以在
the whole village gathered together to take part in this massive fishing activity
一次冰上钓鱼时获得数百公斤的鱼，需要大量的努力，并协调
yakuts are always helping and supporting each other especially when it comes to food they
团队合作，这一过程本身变成了一个群众节，每个
know that without each other's help it's difficult to survive in this cold icy land
村庄都有一个明智的老人，他们非常了解当地的地形，并且将所有
every autumn during manhattan annual ice fishing locals can get several hundred kilograms of fish
当地人聚集在一起，相信动物树木湖泊和火的烈酒，
at a time fishing under the ice demands a lot of effort and coordinated teamwork
然后钓鱼开始本地通过将薄煎饼
the process itself turned into a mass festival
放在火上要求成功钓鱼的森林和湖泊的精神
every village has a wise elderly man who knows the local terrain well
觅食，每个人都感到
and gather all the locals together
兴奋的当地人使多达20人的团队与最有经验的人在一起，通常
believe in the spirits in animals trees lakes and fire before fishing starts local feeds by an eye
是最老的人，是他所代表的领导者他的直觉和经验，决定将网
the spirits of the forest and lakes by putting pancakes on the fire to ask for successful fishing
放在哪里，然后将网络准备就绪，而另
everyone feels excited locals make teams of up to 20 people
一支球队则准备了两个大孔，然后将螺母放在螺母中，然后
with one the most experienced person usually the oldest to be the leader he is acting on
在两个大孔之间制成一系列小孔为了让
his intuition and experience and deciding where to place the net
刀从一端从另一端拉到另一端，然后用钩子
one of the teams then gets the net ready while the other prepares
将木棍带入水中，而另一队在水中使用
two large holes in the eyes in which to be placed the nut
了长棍子，使鱼在水中朝网向网移动，
a series of small holes are then made between the two big ones
因此网络沿几乎整个湖泊的周边都保证了捕获最强的净网
to allow the knife to be pulled from one end to the other using wooden sticks with hooks
的速度更快地阻止鱼逃脱今天
as the nuts get into the water the other team
的女人可以参加传统的冰钓鱼，但在远古时代，
used their long sticks in the water to make the fish move towards the net
只有男人才能参加当地人ALS o相信，一只黑乌鸦在天空
as a result the net runs along almost the entire perimeter of the lake guaranteeing the catch
中盘旋是一个好兆头，他们知道他们不会没有食物，并且在
the strongest pull the net faster prevent the fish from escaping today woman can take part in
冰上钓鱼期间，每个人都会屏住呼吸，当渔民拉出
traditional ice fishing but in ancient times only man could participate in it
他们希望今年有利于冰的网络时，他们会屏住
locals also believe that a black crow circling in the sky is a good sign
呼吸。钓鱼，当渔民终于将网扔掉时，他们不会被没有食物，
they know that they will not be left without food and are frequent guests during the ice fishing
这很幸运，今年很兴奋，非常适合钓鱼当地人
everyone holds their breath when the fishermen pulled the net
有足够的食物来在漫长的寒冷的冬天生存，这就是
they hope this year is favorable for ice fishing and they won't be left without food
为什么Yakutsk Great Moon
when the fishermen finally put the net out everyone feels excited
High High High Fishing
luckily this year was great for fishing locals have enough food to survive the long
像大日子一样另一个令人兴奋且期待已久的
cold winter and that's why Yakutsk great moon high fishing like a big day
部分是分享鱼类的主要角色是与每个
another exciting and long-awaited part is sharing the fish
人分享捕捞量，即使他们不参加他们的几个袋子，他们
the main role is to share the catch with everyone even if they are not taking part
共享几个装满鱼的袋子，并在整个冬季当地人总是在照顾
they share several bags filled with fish and freeze them to eat during the whole winter
。他们在这个湖中不会在这个湖中钓鱼的湖泊三年，以免打扰
locals are always taking care of the lakes they won't do any fishing in this lake for three years
湖的生态平衡，这就是Yakuts在
in order to not disturb the ecological balance of the lake
最冷的居住的PLA中生活和享受生活的方式CE在地球上
this is how Yakuts are living and enjoying their life in the coldest inhabited place on earth
我们相信生活很艰难，但非常美丽
we believe that life is hard but so very beautiful